Girish Chandar G

Ann Arbor, Michigan

OBJECTIVE

Motivated graduate student interested in pursuing Ph.D. in the domain of Computer Vision and Deep Learning focusing on 3D reconstruction, and generation. I have relevant academic knowledge and research experience pertaining to Deep Learning applications in Computer Vision and proficient in Python and use of deep learning frameworks like PyTorch and Tensorflow.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA

M.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Aug 2021 – Apr 2023 GPA - 4/4

Indian Institute of Technology Gandhinagar, Gandhinagar, India

July 2016 - Aug 2020

B.Tech. Electrical Engineering (minor Computer Science)

GPA - 8.98/10

COURSEWORK / SKILLS

- Foundations for Computer Vision (A)
- Matrix Methods for Machine Learning and
 Machine Learning and
- 3D Computer Vision (A)
- PyTorch, Tensorflow, MXNet
- Numpy, OpenCV, Sklearn, Pandas

- Machine Learning (A)
- Signal Processing(A+)
- Deep Learning for Computer Vision (A)
- MATLAB, LabVIEW

• C++

POSITION

Research Assistant | Dr. Xiaoming Liu, Michigan State University

Present

Graduate Student Research Assistant | Dr. Stella Yu, University of Michigan-Ann Arbor

Jan 2023 – Apr 2023

Research Intern | NVIDIA

May 2022 - August 2022

INTERNSHIP

Stereo Hazard Detection | NVIDIA | PyTorch

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- Implemented end-to-end deep learning model using custom UNet as the backbone for feature map extraction.
- Better performance than existing algorithm in terms of achieving zero false positives.

Auto Shape Detection in Machine Vision 🗗 | Zentron Labs | Python (Numpy, OpenCV)

Oct 2020 – Aug 2021

- Implemented Arc Detection algorithm that gives accuracies of 100% on simulated data and 80% on real data.
- Improved Line and Circle Detection accuracies from 65% to 90%

Optimization based Inverse Rendering O University of Texas Dallas | PyTorch, MXNet, Numpy

May 2019 – July 2019

- Implemented algorithm for 3D face reconstruction from 2D images.
- 3D Morphable Model (3DMM) used as aprori mesh for efficient inverse rendering.

Microscopic Image Analysis O Clemson University | LabVIEW

May 2018 – July 2018

• Developed LabVIEW scripts for analyzing images from Magnetic Rotational Spectroscopy (MRS) experiment.

PROJECTS

Epipolar Geometry-Based Artifact Removal in Camera View Projected LiDAR Depth Maps | PyTorch

Apr 2023

Present

• Novel algorithm to remove incorrect depth information from projected depth maps.

SAR-NeRF | PyTorch

•

Research focused on modifying NeRF for 3D reconstruction of complex-valued radar data.

Small NeRF O | PyTorch

Apr 2022

Implemented a modified version of NeRF to reduce training time and computational cost.
Experimented with multiple architectures to determine the best approximation of the original NeRF.

Co-Tuning for Transfer Learning on TACO Dataset PyTorch

Dec 2021

- Implemented and verified the novel transfer algorithm proposed in "Co-tuning for Transfer Learning".
- First team to implement co-tuning on TACO (Trash Annotations in Context) dataset.

Classification of Cancer Progression by Structuring Clinical Data | Tensorflow

Dec 2019

- Developed a novel model to predict the probability of cancer by structuring Electronic Health Records using NLP techniques.
- Explored MIMIC-III dataset extensively and verified its potential to be used for cancer prediction
- Structured the clinical data using CliNER, and BioBERT embedding

Forensic Camera Model Classification using Local Binary Pattern | MATLAB

Apr 2018

- Implemented algorithm to identify source camera from images.
- Implemented One vs All classification model using Local Binary Patterns as features.
- Created novel dataset to test the model.

Unsupervised Cross-Domain Image Transfer using GAN O | PyTorch

Apr 2019

Implemented Encoder+GAN with modified loss and verified the results for cross-domain transfer between MNIST and SVHN.

Patch based Multi-View Stereopsis | Python (Numpy, OpenCV)

Apr 2020

Normalized cuts and segmentation (Numpy, OpenCV)

Apr 2019

Face Detection using Eigenfaces | Python (Numpy, OpenCV)

Dec 2018